Welcome, guys.
The exercise number sixty one, you are asked to write a function that deletes a given note from the
link at list when you insert or delete a note.
You should take care about the linkage about the references between the newly inserted or the deleted
note.
Consider a link to the list here.
It is of.
Three nodes.
And we have this as this as next and this is as previous, this is as next and this is previous and
here is none.
And here is not OK.
If we need to delete this, what what, what will happen with this linkage?
They should be go.
And should the went with, it should be removed.
So this linkage should be removed.
OK.
And we should create new nodes that links the other nodes.
So this node should be linked with this note.
So I should reference this to the next.
This as the previous.
OK.
So when deleting, pay attention to the linkage.
So let's begin making our method.
Delete.
OK.
Think about it.
Host the video.
I think about that.
How should we delete and note how the linkage, how the links will be updated?
I am waiting your solution in the comments below.
So public void delete nodes.
Nodes fill and we start.
This is the base case we start with the first we check if it is had equal equal to null or delete.
Equal equal to none.
Check for not liability.
Always check for it in the liability if had to be equal or equal to none.
Or
deleted.
This is the equal or equal to none.
What we should do, we should return from this message.
The second step is, if not to be deleted, is the head note.
If we delete it, if
the given node is happy, so if had equal equal to deleted, then we move ahead to the next.
OK.
It's very simple.
Guys, we should take care about two possible things.
The first one or three or three?
The first one is deleting the head.
Or deleting a middle note that we have seen in the demonstration before, or we are deleting the last
one.
OK, so these are the cases that we should take care of about it.
So how to make this?
If
they're delayed.
No note is not the first note, then.
If it's not the last.
If they leave, the next does not equal to none.
Then they leave the next door pretty equal to the dog forever.
OK.
It's very simple.
Now, the first step that we should order the first case that we should cover changed, prove only if
known to be be deleted is not the first.
OK.
This is the step behind the check, though the grave does not equal to none other than make down that
grave again next year, called to tell the next.
It's very important this linkage and the return.
It's.
About making their references that should they care about deletion?
That's Ron, Nancy.
We have inserted before that 99 after a ham.
I need to delete it.
So the delete the note before let me run and show you again.
If we run the program without delete node, we have one, nine, nine, two, three and four.
OK, if we delete the note that contains 99 or certainly, here it is the head, we should specify that
al or have let me remove the hat.
OK.
You see the head now it removed one.
So 99 becomes the head two, three and four arteries.
No, it's OK.
You see, guys, how you can delete the note.
You specify here the note.
OK?
It's very important.